I want to talk to you about, or share with you, a breakthrough new approach for managing items of inventory inside of a warehouse. We're talking about a pick, pack and ship setting here. So as a hint, this solution involves hundreds of mobile robots, sometimes thousands of mobile robots, moving around a warehouse. And I'll get to the solution. But for a moment, just think about the last time that you ordered something online. You were sitting on your couch and you decided that you absolutely had to have this red t-shirt. So — click! — you put it into your shopping cart. And then you decided that green pair of pants looks pretty good too — click! And maybe a blue pair of shoes — click! So at this point you've assembled your order. You didn't stop to think for a moment that that might not be a great outfit. But you hit "submit order." And two days later, this package shows up on your doorstep. And you open the box and you're like, wow, there's my goo. Did you ever stop to think about how those items of inventory actually found their way inside that box in the warehouse? So I'm here to tell you it's that guy right there. So deep in the middle of that picture, you see a classic pick-pack worker in a distribution or order fulfillments setting. Classically these pick workers will spend 60 or 70 percent of their day wandering around the warehouse. They'll often walk as much as 5 or 10 miles in pursuit of those items of inventory. Not only is this an unproductive way to fill orders, it also turns out to be an unfulfilling way to fill orders. So let me tell you where I first bumped into this problem. I was out in the Bay area in '99, 2000, the dot com boom. I worked for a fabulously spectacular flame-out called Webvan. (Laughter) This company raised hundreds of millions of dollars with the notion that we will deliver grocery orders online. And it really came down to the fact that we couldn't do it cost effectively. Turns out e-commerce was something that was very hard and very costly. In this particular instance we were trying to assemble 30 items of inventory into a few totes, onto a van to deliver to the home. And when you think about it, it was costing us 30 dollars. Imagine, we had an 89¢ can of soup that was costing us one dollar to pick and pack into that tote. And that's before we actually tried to deliver it to the home. So long story short, during my one year at Webvan, what I realized by talking to all the material-handling providers was that there was no solution designed specifically to solve each base picking. Red item, green, blue, getting those three things in a box. So we said, there's just got to be a better way to do this. Existing material handling was set up to pump pallets and cases of goo to retail stores. Of course Webvan went out of business, and about a year and a half later, I was still noodling on this problem. It was still nagging at me. And I started thinking about it again. And I said, let me just focus briefly on what I wanted as a pick worker, or my vision for how it should work. (Laughter) I said, let's focus on the problem. I have an order here and what I want to do is I want to put red, green and blue in this box right here. What I need is a system where I put out my hand and — poof! — the product shows up and I pack it into the order, and now we're thinking, this would be a very operator-centric approach to solving the problem. This is what I need. What technology is available to solve this problem? But as you can see, orders can come and go, products can come and go. It allows us to focus on making the pick worker the center of the problem, and providing them the tools to make them as productive as possible. So how did I arrive at this notion? Well, actually it came from a brainstorming exercise, probably a technique that many of you use, It's this notion of testing your ideas. Take a blank sheet, of course, but then test your ideas at the limits — infinity, zero. In this particular case, we challenged ourselves with the idea: What if we had to build a distribution center in China, where it's a very, very low-cost market? And say, labor is cheap, land is cheap. And we said specifically, "What if it was zero dollars an hour for direct labor and we could build a million- square-foot distribution center?" So naturally that led to ideas that said, "Let's put lots of people in the warehouse." And I said, "Hold on, zero dollars per hour, what I would do is 'hire' 10,000 workers to come to the warehouse every morning at 8 a.m., walk into the warehouse and pick up one item of inventory and then just stand there. So you hold Captain Crunch, you hold the Mountain Dew, you hold the Diet Coke. If I need it, I'll call you, otherwise just stand there. But when I need Diet Coke and I call it, you guys talk amongst yourselves. Diet Coke walks up to the front — pick it, put it in the tote, away it goes." Wow, what if the products could walk and talk on their own? That's a very interesting, very powerful way that we could potentially organize this warehouse. So of course, labor isn't free, on that practical versus awesome spectrum. (Laughter) So we said mobile shelving — We'll put them on mobile shelving. We'll use mobile robots and we'll move the inventory around. And so we got underway on that and then I'm sitting on my couch in 2008. Did any of you see the Beijing Olympics, the opening ceremonies? I about fell out of my couch when I saw this. I'm like, that was the idea! (Laughter and Applause) We'll put thousands of people on the warehouse floor, the stadium floor. But interestingly enough, this actually relates to the idea in that these guys were creating some incredibly powerful, impressive digital art, all without computers, I'm told, it was all peer-to-peer coordination and communication. You stand up, I'll squat down. And they made some fabulous art. It speaks to the power of emergence in systems when you let things start to talk with each other. So that was a little bit of the journey. So of course, now what became the practical reality of this idea? Here is a warehouse. It's a pick, pack and ship center that has about 10,000 different SKUs. We'll call them red pens, green pens, yellow Post-It Notes. We send the little orange robots out to pick up the blue shelving pods. And we deliver them to the side of the building. So all the pick workers now get to stay on the perimeter. And the game here is to pick up the shelves, take them down the highway and deliver them straight to the pick worker. This pick worker's life is completely different. Rather than wandering around the warehouse, she gets to stay still in a pick station like this and every product in the building can now come to her. So the process is very productive. Reach in, pick an item, scan the bar code, pack it out. By the time you turn around, there's another product there ready to be picked and packed. So what we've done is take out all of the non-value added walking, searching, wasting, waited time, and we've developed a very high-fidelity way to pick these orders, where you point at it with a laser, scan the UPC barcode, and then indicate with a light which box it needs to go into. So more productive, more accurate and, it turns out, it's a more interesting office environment for these pick workers. They actually complete the whole order. So they do red, green and blue, not just a part of the order. And they feel a little bit more in control of their environment. So the side effects of this approach are what really surprised us. We knew it was going to be more productive. But we didn't realize just how pervasive this way of thinking extended to other functions in the warehouse. But what effectively this approach is doing inside of the DC is turning it into a massively parallel processing engine. So this is again a cross-fertilization of ideas. Here's a warehouse and we're thinking about parallel processing supercomputer architectures. The notion here is that you have 10 workers on the right side of the screen that are now all independent autonomous pick workers. If the worker in station three decides to leave and go to the bathroom, it has no impact on the productivity of the other nine workers. Contrast that, for a moment, with the traditional method of using a conveyor. When one person passes the order to you, you put something in and pass it downstream. Everyone has to be in place for that serial process to work. This becomes a more robust way to think about the warehouse. And then underneath the hoods gets interesting in that we're tracking the popularity of the products. And we're using dynamic and adaptive algorithms to tune the floor of the warehouse. So what you see here potentially the week leading up to Valentine's Day. All that pink chalky candy has moved to the front of the building and is now being picked into a lot of orders in those pick stations. Come in two days after Valentine's Day, and that candy, the leftover candy, has all drifted to the back of the warehouse and is occupying the cooler zone on the thermal map there. One other side effect of this approach using the parallel processing is these things can scale to ginormous. (Laughter) So whether you're doing two pick stations, 20 pick stations, or 200 pick stations, the path planning algorithms and all of the inventory algorithms just work. In this example you see that the inventory has now occupied all the perimeter of the building because that's where the pick stations were. They sorted it out for themselves. So I'll conclude with just one final video that shows how this comes to bear on the pick worker's actual day in the life of. So as we mentioned, the process is to move inventory along the highway and then find your way into these pick stations. And our software in the background understands what's going on in each station, we direct the pods across the highway and we're attempting to get into a queuing system to present the work to the pick worker. What's interesting is we can even adapt the speed of the pick workers. The faster pickers get more pods and the slower pickers get few. But this pick worker now is literally having that experience that we described before. She puts out her hand. The product jumps into it. Or she has to reach in and get it. She scans it and she puts it in the bucket. And all of the rest of the technology is kind of behind the scenes. So she gets to now focus on the picking and packing portion of her job. Never has any idle time, never has to leave her mat. And actually we think not only a more productive and more accurate way to fill orders. We think it's a more fulfilling way to fill orders. The reason we can say that, though, is that workers in a lot of these buildings now compete for the privilege of working in the Kiva zone that day. And sometimes we'll catch them on testimonial videos saying such things as, they have more energy after the day to play with their grandchildren, or in one case a guy said, "the Kiva zone is so stress-free that I've actually stopped taking my blood pressure medication." (Laughter) That was at a pharmaceutical distributor, so they told us not to use that video. So what I wanted to leave you with today is the notion that when you let things start to think and walk and talk on their own, interesting processes and productivities can emerge. And now I think next time you go to your front step and pick up that box that you just ordered online, you break it open and the goo is in there, you'll have some wonderment as to whether a robot assisted in the picking and packing of that order. Thank you. (Applause)
Quiero hablarles o compartirles un hito de un nuevo enfoque para administrar artículos de un inventario dentro de un depósito. Hablamos de un escenario de recolectar, empacar, enviar. Como pista, esta solución involucra cientos de robots móviles a veces miles de robots móviles, que se mueven por todo un depósito. Les hablaré de la solución. Pero por un instante, solo piensen en la última vez que pidieron algo en línea. Estaban sentados en su sofá y decidieron que sin duda tenían que comprarse esa camiseta roja. Con un clic lo ponen en su canasta de compras. Luego deciden que ese par de pantalones verdes también se ve bien y clic. Y quizá un par de zapatos azules, clic. En este punto, ya armaron su pedido. En ningún instante se detuvieron a pensar que quizá no es el mejor atuendo. Pero oprimieron 'Enviar pedido'. Dos días después, se presenta el paquete a su puerta. Abren la caja y ¡ups!, ahí tengo mi revoltijo. ¿Se detuvieron a pensar cómo estos artículos del inventario en realidad encontraron su camino hacia la caja en el depósito? Estoy aquí para contarles qué es ese tipo que está ahí. A lo lejos en el centro de la foto, ven a un típico "trabajador de empaque" en un escenario de distribución o de cumplimiento de pedidos. Lo típico es que estos trabajadores dedican de 60 % al 70 % de su día caminando por toda la bodega. A menudo caminan de 7 km a más de 15 km buscando esos artículos del inventario. No solo es esta una forma improductiva de cumplir pedidos, también resulta ser una forma insatisfactoria de cumplir pedidos. Les contaré de cuando me topé con este problema por primera vez. Estaba por San Francisco en 1999-2000, la era de la burbuja del punto com. Trabajaba para una espectacular compañía llamada Webvan. (Risas) Esta compañía recaudó cientos de millones de dólares con la idea de hacer entregas de abarrotes por compras en línea. Llegamos a la conclusión de que no podíamos tener costos eficientes. Resultó que el comercio electrónico era difícil y muy costoso. En ese momento particular intentamos reunir 30 artículos de inventario en unos cuantos acarreos, en una camioneta para entregar a domicilio. Si lo piensan, nos costaba USD 30. Imaginen, teníamos una lata de sopa de 89 centavos que nos costaba un dólar recolectarlo y empacarlo para su trasiego. Y eso era antes de intentar la entrega a domicilio. Para acortar la historia, en mi primer año en Webvan, me di cuenta al hablar con todos los distintos proveedores que no había una solución específica diseñada para cada base de recolección. Artículo rojo, verde, azul, poner esas 3 cosas en una caja. Nos dijimos, tiene que haber una mejor forma de hacer esto. El manejo de materiales existente está armado para mover tarimas y cajas a las tiendas. Claro que Webvan quebró y como un año y medio después, todavía estaba pensando en este problema, me seguía molestando. Y empecé a pensarlo otra vez. Me dije: "Me voy a centrar en lo que quiero como trabajador de empaque". Cuál es mi visión de cómo debe funcionar... (Risas) Me dije: "Enfócate en el problema". Tengo un pedido aquí y lo que quiero es poner rojo, verde y azul en esta caja. Lo que necesito es un sistema donde ponga mi mano y ¡puf! los productos aparecen y completo el pedido y ahora estamos pensando, "sería un enfoque muy centrado en el operador para solucionar el problema. Eso es lo que necesito, ¿qué tecnología existe para solucionar este problema?" Pero como ven, los pedidos van y vienen, los productos van y vienen. Nos permite enfocar al trabajador de empaque como el centro del problema y dotarlo con herramientas para hacerlos tan productivos como sea posible. ¿Cómo llegué a esta noción? En realidad vino de un ejercicio de lluvia de ideas, una técnica que probablemente muchos de Uds. usan, es esta noción de probar sus ideas. Toman una hoja en blanco, luego prueban sus ideas al límite. Al infinito, cero... En este caso particular, nos retamos con la idea: ¿qué tal si tuviéramos que construir un centro de distribución en China, donde el costo de mercado es muy bajo? Digamos, que la mano de obra es barata, el suelo es barato. Y decimos específicamente: "¿Qué tal si fuera cero dólares la hora de trabajo directo y pudiéramos construir un centro de distribución de 93 000 m²?" Eso naturalmente conduce a ideas como: "Pongamos a mucha gente en el depósito". A lo que dije: "Esperen, cero dólares por hora, lo que haría es 'contratar' a 10 000 trabajadores que acudan al depósito cada mañana a las 8 horas, caminen por el depósito y recojan un artículo del inventario y luego que solo se paren ahí. Entonces tú tienes la barra de Cap'n Crunch, tú el Mountain Dew y tú la Diet Coke. Si la necesito, les llamo, si no solo esperan ahí. Pero cuando necesito una Diet Coke y les llamo, hablan entre Uds. Diet Coke aparece, lo recolecto, lo trasiego y está en camino". ¡Caramba!, ¿qué tal si los productos pudieran caminar y hablar por su cuenta? Esa es una forma poderosa e interesante de potenciar la organización del depósito. Claro está, que la mano de obra no es gratis, lo práctico versus el espectro fabuloso. (Risas) Así dijimos estantería móvil, los pondremos en estanterías móviles. Usaremos robots móviles y moveremos el inventario. Nos pusimos manos a la obra en eso cuando sentado en mi sofá en 2008... ¿Vieron la ceremonia de apertura de los JJ.OO. de Beijing? Por poco me caigo del sofá cuando vi eso. ¡Eso es! (Risas) (Aplausos) Pondremos a miles de personas en el piso del depósito, el piso del estadio. Resulta curioso, esto está relacionado con la idea de crear arte digital impresionante increíblemente poderoso, todo sin computadora, me dijeron, era todo coordinación y comunicación punto a punto. Tú te paras, yo me agacho. E hicieron arte fabuloso. Habla del poder del surgimiento en sistemas cuando dejan que las cosas empiecen a hablar entre sí. Eso fue una partecita de la travesía. Por supuesto, ¿de esta idea qué se convirtió en realidad práctica? Aquí está un depósito, un centro de recolección, empaque y envío con unos 10 mil números de referencia. Les llamamos plumas rojas, plumas verdes y post-it amarillos. Mandamos pequeños robots naranjas para recoger anaqueles azules y los entregamos a un lado del edificio. Así todos los trabajadores de recolección permanecen en la periferia. La maniobra aquí es recolectar los anaqueles, ponerlos en la banda y entregarlos directamente al trabajador de empaque. La vida de los trabajadores es completamente diferente. En vez de vagar por el depósito, permanecen quietos en una estación de recolección como ésta y cada producto en el edificio puede ahora llegarles. Así el proceso es muy productivo, a su alcance, recolecta un artículo, escanea el código de barra, lo empaca. Cuando se dan la vuelta, hay otro producto listo para ser recolectado y empacado. Eliminamos todo el tiempo de espera, perdido, de búsqueda, de caminar sin valor agregado y desarrollamos un forma de alta confiabilidad de recolección de pedidos, donde apuntan con un láser, escanean el código electrónico y luego indican con una luz a cuál caja debe ir. Es más productivo, más preciso y resulta que es un ambiente de trabajo más interesante para estos trabajadores. De hecho cumplen con todo el pedido. Así que hacen rojo, verde y azul y no solo una parte. Se sienten un poco más en control de su ambiente. Así los efectos secundarios de este enfoque es lo que en verdad nos sorprendió. Sabíamos que iba a ser más productivo. Pero no nos dimos cuenta cómo se fue permeando esta forma de pensar en otras funciones del depósito. La efectividad de este enfoque dentro del centro de distribución es que lo transforma en una máquina de procesamiento paralelo masivo. Otra vez, esto es una fertilización cruzada de ideas. Aquí hay un depósito y estamos pensando en arquitecturas de supercomputadora de procesamiento en paralelo. La noción aquí es que tienen 10 trabajadores a la derecha de la pantalla ahora todos son trabajadores de empaque autónomos independientes. Si el trabajador de la estación 3 necesita ir al baño, no hay impacto en la productividad de los otros 9 trabajadores. Contrasten eso, con el método tradicional del uso de la banda transportadora. Cuando alguien les pasa el pedido, le ponen algo y lo pasan a la banda corriendo. Todos tienen que estar en su lugar para que el proceso en serie funcione. Esto se convierte en una forma más robusta de concebir el depósito. Debajo del toldo se pone interesante porque estamos rastreando la popularidad de los productos. Y estamos usando algoritmos adaptativos y dinámicos para ajustar el piso del depósito. Lo que ven aquí es la semana previa al día de San Valentín. Todo el dulce polvoso rosa se ha movido al frente del edificio y se recolecta para llenar pedidos en las estaciones de recolección. Vengan 2 días después de San Valentín y el dulce que quedó, todo se ha recorrido a la parte posterior del depósito y ocupa la zona más templada en el mapa térmico aquí. Otro efecto secundario de este enfoque que usa el procesamiento en paralelo es que estas cosas se pueden escalar a lo 'hipergigante'. (Risas) Sea que tengan 2 estaciones de recolección, 20 estaciones o 200 estaciones, los algoritmos de planeación de ruta y todos los algoritmos de inventario funcionan. En este ejemplo ven que el inventario ocupa ahora todo el perímetro del edificio, porque es ahí donde están las estaciones de recolección. Los clasifican ellos mismos. Concluyo con un video final que muestra cómo se desarrolla esto en un día de la vida del trabajador de empaque Como dijimos, el proceso es mover el inventario por la carretera y luego encuentra su camino hacia las estaciones de recolección. Nuestro software tras bambalinas entiende lo que pasa en cada estación, dirigimos el depósito por toda la carretera e intentamos ponerlo en una sistema de cola que presente el trabajo al trabajador de empaque. Lo interesante es que podemos adaptar la velocidadde recolección de los trabajadores. Los más rápidos obtienen más anaqueles y los más lentos, menos. Pero el trabajador ahora experimenta cabalmente lo que describimos antes. Saca su mano, el producto le brinca o tiene que alzarlo y tomarlo. Lo escanea y lo pone en la canasta. Y todo el resto de la tecnología está tras bambalinas. Así el trabajador se concentra en la parte de recolección y empaque. Nunca tiene tiempos muertos ni tiene que dejar su puesto. De hecho pensamos que no solo es más productivo y más preciso para cumplir los pedidos sino que creemos que es una forma más satisfactoria de cumplir pedidos. Podemos decir esto porque los trabajadores en muchos de estos edificios ahora compiten por el privilegio de trabajar en la zona KIVA. Y a veces los sorprendemos en videos testimoniales diciendo cosas como que tienen más energía al final del día para jugar son sus nietos o en una ocasión alguien dijo, "En la zona KIVA no hay estrés y de hecho he dejado de tomar la medicina para la presión". (Risas) Eso fue con un distribuidor farmacéutico, que nos pidió que no usáramos ese video. Hoy quiero dejarles la noción de que cuando dejan que las cosas empiecen a pensar y caminar y que hablen por su cuenta, surgen procesos interesantes y productivos. Creo que el siguiente paso es que vayan a la puerta, recojan esa caja de lo que pidieron en línea, la abran y el revoltijo esté ahí; sentirán cierto asombro de si un robot asistió en la recolección y empaque de ese pedido. Gracias. (Aplausos)